Guide to the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations oral history collection 2011.019
Brooklyn Historical Society
Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations oral history collection
2011-2014
2011.019
Brooklyn Historical Society
709.0 gigabytes of oral history interviews with 107 narrators. Collection includes transcripts, audio recordings, and photographs formatted as .wav, .mp3, .pdf, .jpg, and .png files, in addition to 3 linear feet of paper transcripts.
Brooklyn Historical Society (Brooklyn, New York, N.Y.).
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged alphabetically by the narrator's last name.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains materials from the CBBG oral history project. Included are transcripts and audio recordings of interviews conducted by 25 oral historians with 107 narrators. Also included are photographs of the narrators and their families. The oral histories were conducted as life history interviews; topics of discussion include self and identity; religion and tradition; laws and mores; food and celebration; love and marriage; parents and children; race and ethnicity; and cultural preservation.
Historical note
Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations (CBBG) was an oral history project and public programming series sponsored by Brooklyn Historical Society from 2011 to 2014. CBBG was designed to examine the history and experiences of mixed-heritage people and families in Brooklyn. The project also explored the broader themes of cultural hybridity, race, ethnicity, and identity formation in the United States. CBBG was created by Sady Sullivan, Director of Oral History at Brooklyn Historical Society from 2006-2014, and the project was funded with assistance from public and private grants. CBBG expanded upon Brooklyn Historical Society’s oral history collection, which was founded in 1973 and contains interviews with over 1200 narrators.
Conditions Governing Access note
Oral histories can be accessed onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online at the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org.
Please see the Oral History Note for guidelines on using Brooklyn Historical Society's oral history collections.
Oral History note
Oral history interviews are intimate conversations between two people, both of whom have agreed to share the recordings with Brooklyn Historical Society and with researchers. Please listen in the spirit with which these were shared. Researchers will understand that:
1. Brooklyn Historical Society abides by the General Principles & Best Practices for Oral History as agreed upon by the Oral History Association (2009) and expects that use of this material will be done with respect for these professional ethics.
2.This transcript is a nearly verbatim copy of the recorded interview. As such, it may contain the natural false starts, verbal stumbles, misspeaks, and repetitions that are common in conversation. This decision was made because Brooklyn Historical Society gives primacy to the audible voice and also because some researchers do find useful information in these verbal patterns.
3.Unless these verbal patterns are germane to your scholarly work, when quoting from this material researchers are encouraged to correct the grammar and make other modifications maintaining the flavor of the narrator’s speech while editing the material for the standards of print.
Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Bullying in schools; Cultural diversity; Digital Photographs; Education; Gentrification; Interfaith families; Interviews (sound recordings); Mixed heritage; Oral histories (document genres); Passing (Identity); Privilege; Queer identity; Race identity; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; Racism; Religious identity; Transcripts; United States |x Emigration and immigration
- Sophia Agag, 2014 March 18; 2011.019.081
  Biographical note
  Sophia Agag was born to an Italian American mother and an Algerian American father and raised in the Astoria neighborhood of Queens. Agag majored in mass communication at LaGuardia Community College in Queens, New York. She also served as a volunteer with the Arab American Association of New York, an organization dedicated to helping Arab American children develop English literacy skills.
  Scope and Contents
  In the interview, Agag discusses her childhood in the Astoria neighborhood of Queens; parents' courtship and marriage; father's Berber heritage; career aspirations; international travel experiences; work with the Arab American Association of New York; and impressions of ethnic and cultural diversity in Astoria. Interview conducted by Amna Ahmad.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library. The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.
  Arab Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Astoria (New York, N.Y.); Berbers |z New York (State) |z New York; Cultural diversity; Interethnic marriage; Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z Queens County; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; United States |x Emigration and immigration
- Katherine Ambia, 2012 January 14; 2012 January 22; 2011.019.009.013
  Katherine Ambia was born to a white American mother and a Peruvian father and raised in the Sunset Park neighborhood of Brooklyn. Ambia received a B.A. in Latin American studies from Wesleyan University in Middletown, Connecticut, where she co-founded the Multiracial Student Network. She received an M.S. in social work from Columbia University in New York City and worked as a clinical fellow at the Yale Child Study Center in New Haven, Connecticut.
  In the interview, Ambia discusses her racial identity; educational experiences; aspirations to pursue a career in family therapy; father's childhood in Chincheros and Lima, Peru; mother's childhood in New York City; and parents' courtship, marriage, divorce and work as community organizers in the 1970s. Interview conducted by Amna Ahmad.
  Education |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Peru; Peruvian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Race identity; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; Social work; Spanish language; Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)
- Kai Michael Denn Ando, 2013 February 5; 2011.019.044
  Kai Michael Denn Ando was born to a white American mother and a Japanese American father in Seattle, Washington. He was raised in Seattle and New York City. Ando received a B.M. in jazz performance and double bass from the New England Conservatory of Music in Boston, Massachusetts. He worked in the music and publishing industries.
  In the interview, Ando discusses his parents' marriage, divorce, and remarriages; relatives' experiences of World War II in the United States and Japan; experiences living on the East and West Coasts; and personal health issues, including a bout with cancer. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.
  Boston (Mass.); Cancer |x Patients; Education |z New York (State) |z New York; Education, Higher |z Massachusetts |z Boston; Japanese Americans |x World War, 1939-1945; Japanese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Musicians |z New York (State) |z New York; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; Seattle (Wash.)
- Sergia Andrade, 2013 May 29; 2013 November 25; 2011.019.047
  Sergia Andrade was born to Cabo Verdean parents in France. She was raised in the Boerum Hill neighborhood of Brooklyn and attended boarding school in Wellesley, Massachusetts. Andrade received a B.A. in international studies from City College and studied social work at Hunter College, both located in New York City. She worked as a case coordinator at the Vera Institute of Justice.
  In the interviews, Andrade discusses her racial and political identities; encounters with racism; appreciation of African and Caribbean cultures; parents' courtship, marriage, and divorce; maternal grandparents' ethnic and racial identities; father's experiences with racism and segregation in colonial Cabo Verde; and experiences raising her children in Brooklyn, New York. Interviews conducted by Charis Shafer.
  Boarding schools |z Massachusetts |z Wellesley; Boerum Hill (New York, N.Y.); Cabo Verde; Cabo Verdeans |z Portugal; France; Interpersonal racism; Race identity; Racially mixed people; Racism in education; Social work |z New York (State); United States |x Emigration and immigration
- Ericka Basile, 2014 June 4; 2011.019.095
  Ericka Basile was born to Haitian parents and raised in Johnson City, Tennessee. She received a B.F.A. in painting from East Tennessee State University in Johnson City and an M.A. in visual culture: costume studies from New York University in New York City. Basile lived in the Bedford–Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn and worked as a writer, artist and independent fashion scholar.
  In the interview, Basile discusses her family's African, French, and Taíno ancestry; educational experiences and learning French and Creole; exposure to the West Indian community in New York City; parents' emigration from Haiti; and mother's childhood in Brooklyn and Queens, New York. Interview conducted by Jennifer Scott.
  Access to the interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org. The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.
  Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.); Creole dialects, French; Education |z Tennessee |z Johnson City; Haiti; Haitian Americans |z Tennessee |z Johnson City; Johnson City (Tenn.); Race identity; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; Springfield Gardens (New York, N.Y.); United States |x Emigration and immigration; West Indian Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County
- Pete Beveridge, 2012 May 23; 2011.019.032
  Pete Beveridge was born to white American parents in Newton, Massachusetts and raised in New York City. He received a B.A. in history from Harvard University in Cambridge, Massachusetts and an M.A. in African history from Columbia University in New York City. He is the author of Domestic Diversity, a memoir.
  In the interview, Beveridge discusses his student life; interest in African history, civil rights, and communism; political activism that led to FBI scrutiny; courtship and marriage to his African American wife; prejudice and racism they experienced as an interracial couple in the 1950s and 1960s; and adopting and raising his son. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.
  African Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Community activists |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Discrimination in housing |z New York (State) |z New York; Education, Higher |z New York (State) |z New York; Interracial marriage; Racially mixed families; Segregation |z New York (State) |z New York
- Jonathan Blazon, 2012 February 25; 2011.019.022
  Jonathan Blazon was born to a Chinese American mother and a French Canadian father and raised in Concord, New Hampshire and Brooklyn, New York. He attended the School of Visual Arts in New York City and the École nationale supérieure des Beaux-Arts in Paris, France. He worked as a director and managing partner at Primera Languages for Business in New York City.
  In the interview, Blazon discusses his racial identity; experiences of racism and rejection from white Americans and Chinese Americans; parents' courtship and marriage; maternal relatives' Chinese restaurant in New Hampshire; and aspirations for his daughter to navigate her own mixed heritage. Interview conducted by Cynthia Lee.
  Related Archival Materials
  Oral history interview with Jonathan Blazon's mother, Bette Yee, 2011.019.021.
  Bullying in schools |z New Hampshire; Chinese Americans |z New Hampshire; Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; French-Canadians |z New Hampshire; New Hampshire; Parenthood; Paris (France); Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); Race identity; Racially ambiguous people; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people
- Sheila Bligen and Barbara Chambers, 2014 May 6; 2011.019.086
  Sheila Bligen was born to African American parents and raised in New York City. She graduated from the Julia Richmond High School in Manhattan, New York and worked at Verizon Communications.
  Barbara Chambers was born to African American parents in Darby, Pennsylvania and raised in the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn. She attended Midwood High School in Brooklyn, New York and worked as a secretary with the United States Department of Defense and at Verizon Communications.
  In the interview, Blingen and Chambers both discuss their childhoods in New York City; courtship and marriage; artistic interests; and impressions of the Civil Rights Movement. Interview conducted by Rebecca Jacobs.
  Artists |z New York (State) |z New York; Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.); Education |z New York (State) |z New York; Pennsylvania; Queer identity; Same-sex marriage; Work environment |z New York (State) |z New York
- Leina Bocar, 2013 June 12; 2011.019.049
  Leina Bocar was born to an Irish American mother and a Filipino father in Oklahoma. Bocar received a B.F.A. from the School of the Art Institute of Chicago in Illinois and studied at the Slade School of Fine Art in London, England, Metàfora in Barcelona, Spain, and the New School in New York City.
  In the interview, Bocar discusses her racially ambiguous appearance; involvement in the artistic community; participation in the Occupy Wall Street movement; political convictions; encounters with racism; parents' courtship and marriage; trips to the Philippines; and family's Christian traditions. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.
  Artists |z Illinois |z Chicago; Education, Higher |z Illinois |z Chicago; Filipinos |z Oklahoma; Occupy movement |z New York (State) |z New York; Oklahoma; Philippines; Race identity; Racially ambiguous people; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.); United States |x Emigration and immigration
- Vilray Bolles, 2012 February 9; 2012 February 29; 2011.019.017.023
  Vilray Bolles was born to a Nicaraguan American mother and a white American father and raised in New York City. Bolles attended the New England Conservatory of Music in Boston, Massachusetts. He worked as a musician and also for Edison Price Lighting, a lighting fixture company in Queens, New York.
  In the interviews, Bolles discusses his family; parents' courtship and marriage; maternal grandfather's involvement in the Nicaraguan military; paternal grandparents' interfaith marriage; educational experiences; involvement in the music community; and an experience of arrest with false accusations of terrorism. Interviews conducted by Manissa Maharawal.
  Related Archival Materials note
  Oral history interview with Vilray Bolles's friend, Hansraj Maharawal, 2011.019.034.
  Arrest |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Education |z New York (State) |z New York; Education, Higher |z Massachusetts |z Boston; Interfaith families; Nicaragua; Nicaraguan Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); Race identity; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; War on Terrorism, 2001-2009
- Daniela Caraballo, 2011 December 18; 2011.019.007
  Daniela Caraballo was born to a Dominican American mother and Puerto Rican father and raised in New York City. Caraballo received a B.A. in psychology from Bryn Mawr College in Pennsylvania and an M.S.W. from Hunter College in New York City. She was employed as a social worker in New York City.
  In the interview, Caraballo discusses her Puerto Rican and Dominican heritage; educational experiences; parents' courtship, marriage, divorce; childhood experiences with custody arrangements following her mother's move to Florida; and career in social work. Interview conducted by Margaret Fraser.
  Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Dominican Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Education |z New York (State) |z New York; Education, Higher |z Pennsylvania |z Bryn Mawr; Interethnic marriage; Parental relocation (Child custody) |z Florida; Puerto Ricans |z New York (State) |z New York; Social workers |z New York (State) |z New York
- Natalie Chassler, 2013 August 29; 2014 January 14; 2011.019.062
  Natalie Chassler was born to white American Jewish parents and raised in Brooklyn, New York. Chassler attended Hunter College and the New York School of Social Work, both located in New York City. She was employed as a social worker and director of the Manhattan Psychiatric Center.
  In the interviews, Chassler discusses her childhood in the East Flatbush and Crown Heights neighborhoods of Brooklyn during the Great Depression; courtship and marriage to her husband; adult friendships; and personal and professional relationships with people who suffer from mental illness. Interviews conducted by Charis Shafer.
  Chicago (Ill.); Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.); East Flatbush (New York, N.Y.); Great Depression |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Jews, American |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Psychiatric Hospitals |z New York (State) |z New York; Slavery |z United States; Social workers |z New York (State) |z New York; World War, 1939-1945
- Sara Casten and Eduardo Cruz, 2014 February 14; 2011.019.076
  Sara Casten was born to white American Jewish parents and raised in Massachusetts. Casten received an M.S. in historic preservation and conservation from the University of Vermont in Burlington. She studied art education at Brooklyn College in New York City and worked as an administrative associate at the Brooklyn Historical Society.
  Eduardo Cruz was born to Mexican parents and raised in Hidalgo, Mexico. Cruz attended Centro De Bachillerato Tecnologico Agropecuario Número 6 in Molango, Mexico. He worked as a primary school teacher in Mexico and in the food services industry in New York City.
  In the interviews, Casten and Cruz discuss their courtship; efforts to overcome language barriers; and impressions of familial structure, gender roles, and community in Mexican and American cultures. Casten discusses her experiences living in New York City during a recession. Cruz describes his immigration experience. Interviews conducted by Nadia Williams.
  Education |z Mexico; English as a second language; Hidalgo (Mexico); Interfaith dating; Interracial dating; Massachusetts; Mexicans |z New York (State) |z New York; Sex role; Spanish language; United States |x Emigration and immigration
- Daniel Aldana Cohen, 2013 June 20; 2011.019.050
  Daniel Aldana Cohen was born to a Guatemalan mother and a white Canadian Jewish father in Toronto, Canada. He was raised in Toronto and Paris, France. Cohen received a B.A. in intellectual history and development studies from McGill University in Montreal, Canada. He lived in the Prospect Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn and pursued a Ph.D. in sociology at New York University located in New York City.
  In the interview, Cohen discusses his Jewish and Guatemalan heritage; encounters with racism in France; educational experiences; parents' courtship and marriage; views on Zionism; and encounters with anti-Semitism. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.
  Education |z France |z Paris; Education, Higher |z Québec |z Montréal; Guatemalans |z Canada; Interfaith families; Jews, Canadian; Paris (France); Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; Toronto (Ont.); Zionism
- Adam Collado, 2013 September 7; 2011.019.060
  Adam Collado was born to a Puerto Rican mother and a Dominican father in New York City. He grew up in the East New York neighborhood of Brooklyn and received a B.A. in economics from Brooklyn College in New York City. He worked as a technology coordinator at a high school in the Dumbo neighborhood of Brooklyn.
  In the interview, Collado discusses his parents' adolescent years, courtship, and marriage; educational experiences in the Greenpoint neighborhood of Brooklyn; employment in New York City public high schools; relatives' experiences with drug trafficking and addiction in the East New York neighborhood of Brooklyn; and childhood exposure to violent crime in East New York. Interview conducted by Charis Shafer.
  Oral history with Adam Collado's cousin, Amy Collado, 2011.019.070.
  Brownsville (New York, N.Y.); Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Dominican Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Drug traffic |z New York (State) |z Kings County; East New York (New York, N.Y.); Education |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Interethnic marriage; Puerto Ricans |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Racism in education |z New York (State) |z New York
- Amy Collado, 2013 November 11; 2011.019.070
  Amy Collado was born to a Dominican American mother in New York City and raised in the East New York neighborhood of Brooklyn. She worked on Open City Mixtape, a collection of narrative and documentary films about New York City.
  In the interview, Collado discusses her family; close relationship with her cousin, Adam Collado; relatives' experiences with drug trafficking and addiction in the East New York neighborhood of Brooklyn; maternal grandfather's racial prejudices; and impressions of gentrification in Brooklyn, particularly in the Williamsburg neighborhood of Brooklyn. Interview conducted by Charis Shafer.
  Oral history with Amy Collado's cousin, Adam Collado, 2011.019.060.
  Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Dominican Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Drug traffic |z New York (State) |z Kings County; East New York (New York, N.Y.); Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Interpersonal racism; Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.)
- Alexander David, 2012 January 13; 2011.019.011
  Alexander David was born to a Chinese American mother and a Jewish Canadian father in New York City. He was raised in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn and attended Stuyvesant High School in Manhattan, New York, where he played a variety of sports and founded a club for mixed race students. David studied biomedical engineering as a Macaulay Honors student at City College of New York in New York City.
  In the interview, David discusses his racial identity; childhood in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn; parents' courtship and marriage; and academic, social, and athletic experiences in middle school, high school, and college. Interview conducted by Amna Ahmad.
  Access to the full interview is available onsite at the Brooklyn Historical Society's Othmer Library and online on the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations website: cbbg.brooklynhistory.org. The Brooklyn Historical Society does not have permission to license oral history audio recordings or transcripts to third parties.
  Education |z New York (State) |z New York; Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); Race identity; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; School sports |z New York (State) |z New York; Student life and customs |z New York (State) |z New York
- Amalia della Paolera, 2013 Dec 30; 2014 March 20; 2011.019.088
  Amalia della Paolera was born to a white American mother and an Argentinian father and raised in the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn. Della Paolera received a B.A. in Latin American studies from Harvard University in Cambridge, Massachusetts and an M.B.A. from Harvard Business School.
  In the interview, della Paolera discusses her parents' courtship and marriage; father's immigration to the United States; childhood in the Fort Greene neighborhood of Brooklyn during the 1980s; and impressions of racial, ethnic, and economic diversity in Fort Greene. Interview conducted by Senait Tesfai.